In this video, I'm going to talk about
本节视频将讨论
the Sass Ampersand and how you can use it to write some really cool Sass.
Sass 的 &amp; 符号以及如何使用它编写出色的 Sass
Take a look at this piece of Sass.
看看这段 Sass
If this were normal Sass and you didn't have the Ampersand here,
如果这是一段普通的 Sass 里面没有 &amp; 号的话
this would be talking about a parent element that
表示的是一个 parent 元素
had an element of class section inside of it.
内部有一个类名为 section 的元素
But when you do put the Ampersand here,
但是当你在这里放一个 &amp; 号时
you change it so that you're talking about a parent that also has a class of section.
意思就不同了 这样就表示 parent 同时也有 section 类属性
If you put it into CSS,
如果将其转换成 CSS
it would look like this,
看起来就是这样子
where it is a parent and a section class on the same element.
同一个元素上既有 parent 类又有 section 类
Now, this might look a little bit
现在 看起来可能不太好理解
underwhelming until you think about its potentially uses.
我们来设想一下其用途
When you get this Ampersand,
当代码中有 ＆ 号时
it gives you the ability to style something that is a parent and that's something you
它使你能够设置父级元素的样式
never had in CSS before and it's one of
这在 CSS 中从没有出现过
the truly unique Sass extensions that makes Sass so awesome.
是 Sass 真正独有的出色扩展
If you take a look at this,
看一下这段代码
you'll see one of the more common implementations of the Ampersand in Sass.
你会看到 Sass 中的 ＆ 号的更常见实现之一
Here, we have a button,
这里 我们有一个按钮
it could just as easily be a link or something else and inside,
可能就是一个简单的链接或者其他东西
we have nested all of the related styles.
其中 嵌套了所有相关样式
This is a really great way to organize your styles just because it keeps
这真的是一种很好的样式组织方式 因为它可以保持
all of them neatly encapsulated in one easily recognizable place.
所有样式都整齐地封装在一个易于识别的地方
But this would be a problem without the Ampersand.
如果没有 ＆ 号 这会有一个问题
Because if I wanted to say that the button had a hover state,
如果我想让按钮有一个悬停的状态
I would have to re-declare this button and its class below and add the hover state,
必须在下面重新声明这个按钮和它的类 添加悬停状态
but in this case,
但是在当前示例中
with the Sass Ampersand,
有了 Sass 的 &amp; 号
I can declare extra properties on this parent just by using this Ampersand.
使用 ＆ 号就可以在父级下声明更多属性
So this is the same as me saying button.ctahover.
所以 这里表达的意思与 button.cta:hover 是一样的
When you use the Ampersand with pseudo selectors,
当你将 ＆ 号与伪类选择器一起使用时
they become super powerful.
两者都将变得超级强大
Another really great place to use this is with animations.
另一个非常好的场景是与动画一起使用
Once you master the Sass Ampersand,
一旦掌握了 Sass 的 ＆ 号
you will be well on your way to writing much better Sass style sheets.
你将能以自己的方式编写更好的 Sass 样式表